Help! Help!
Hey, pea brain!
Help!
Do something!
- What?
- Anything!
- Hurry up!
- Swish and flick.
Wingardium Leviosa.
Cool.
Is it dead?
I don't think so. Just knocked out.
Troll boogers.
Oh, my goodness! Explain yourselves,
both of you!
- Well, what it is--
- It's my fault, Professor McGonagall.
Miss Granger?
I went looking for the troll. I
thought I could handle it.
But I was wrong.
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found
me, I'd probably be dead.
Be that as it may, it was an extremely
foolish thing to do.
I expected more rational behavior and
am very disappointed in you.
Five points will be taken from
Gryffindor...
...for your serious lack of judgment.
As for you two gentlemen...
...I just hope you realize how
fortunate you are.
Not many first-year students could
take on a troll...
...and live to tell the tale.
Five points...
...will be awarded to each of you...
...for sheer dumb luck.
Perhaps you ought to go. It might wake
up.
Take a bit of toast, mate. Go on.
Ron's right. You'll need your strength
today.
I'm not hungry.
Good luck today, Potter. You've proven
yourself against a troll.
A game of Quidditch should be easy
work.
Even if it is against Slytherin.
- That explains the blood.
- Blood?
Last night, I'm guessing Snape let the
troll in as a diversion...
...so he could get past that dog.
But he got bit, that's why he's
limping.
But why would anyone go near that dog?
At Gringotts, Hagrid took something
out of the vault.
Said it was Hogwarts business, very
secret.
You're saying--
That's what the dog's guarding. That's
what Snape wants.
- Bit early for mail, isn't it?
- But I never get mail.
Let's open it.
It's a broomstick.
That's not just a broomstick, it's a
Nimbus 2000!
But who--?
- Scared, Harry?
- A little.
It's all right. I felt the same way
before my first game.
- What happened?
- I don't really remember.
I took a Bludger to the head two
minutes in.
Woke up in hospital a week later.
Welcome to Hogwarts'first Quidditch
game of the season.
Today's game, Slytherin versus
Gryffindor!
The players take their positions...
...as Madam Hooch steps onto the field
to begin the game!
Now, I want a nice, clean game...
...from all of you!
The Bludgers are up, followed by the
Golden Snitch.
Remember, the Snitch is worth 150
points.
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends
the game.
The Quaffle is released and the game
begins!
Angelina Johnson scores! Ten points
for Gryffindor!
Well done!
Slytherin takes the Quaffle. Bletchley
passes to Captain Marcus Flint.
Another 10 points to Gryffindor!
Give me that!
Take that side!
What's going on with Harry's
broomstick?
It's Snape. He's jinxing the broom!
- Jinxing the broom? What do we do?
- Leave it to me.
Come on, Hermione!
Lacarnum Inflamarae.
Fire! You're on fire!
Go, go, go, go!
Looks like he's gonna be sick.
He's got the Snitch!
Harry Potter receives 150 points for
catching the Snitch!
Gryffindor wins!
Nonsense! Why would Snape put a curse
on Harry's broom?
Who knows? Why was he trying to get
past that three-headed dog?
- Who told you about Fluffy?
- Fluffy?
- That thing has a name?
- Of course he has a name. He's mine.
I bought him off an Irishman. I lent
him to Dumbledore to guard--
Shouldn't have said that. No more
questions! That's top-secret.
But whatever Fluffy's guarding,
Snape's trying to steal it.
Codswallop. Professor Snape is a
Hogwarts teacher.
Teacher or not, I know a spell when I
see one. I've read all about them.
You've got to keep eye contact, and
Snape wasn't blinking.
Exactly.
Now, you listen to me, all three of
you.
You're meddling in things that ought
not to be meddled in. It's dangerous.
What that dog is guarding is between
Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel.
Nicholas Flamel?
I shouldn't have said that. I should
not have said that.
Nicholas Flamel. Who's Nicholas
Flamel?
I don't know.
Merry Christmas Merry Christmas
Ring the Hogwart bell
Cast a Christmas spell
Knight to E-5.
Queen to E-5.
That's totally barbaric!
That's wizard's chess. I see you've
packed.
I see you haven't.
Change of plans. My parents went to
Romania to visit my brother Charlie.
- He's studying dragons there.
- Good. You can help Harry.
He's going to the library to look up
Nicholas Flamel.
We've looked a hundred times!
Not in the restricted section. Happy
Christmas.
I think we've had a bad influence on
her.
Harry, wake up! Come on, Harry, wake
up!
- Happy Christmas, Harry.
- Happy Christmas, Ron.
What are you wearing?
Oh, my mum made it. Looks like you've
got one too.
- I've got presents?
- Yeah.
There they are.
"Your father left this in my
possession before he died.
It is time it was returned to you. Use
it well."
- What is it?
- Some kind of cloak.
Well, let's see, then. Put it on.
My body's gone!
I know what that is. That's an
invisibility cloak!
I'm invisible?
They're really rare. I wonder who gave
it to you.
There was no name. It just said, "Use
it well."
Famous Fire-Eaters. Fifteenth-Century
Fiends.
Flamel. Nicholas Flamel. Where are
you?
Who's there?
I know you're in there. You can't
hide.
Who is it? Show yourself.
Severus, I....
You don't want me as your enemy,
Quirrell.
- I don't know what you mean.
- You know perfectly well what I mean.
We'll have another little chat soon.
When you've had time to decide where
your loyalties lie.
Professors. I found this in the
restricted section.
It's still hot. That means there's a
student out of bed.
Mum?
Dad?
Ron, you've really gotta see this!
Ron, you've gotta see this!
Ron, come on, get out of bed!
- Why?
- There's something you've got to see!
Come on! Come! Come look, it's my
parents!
I only see us.
Look in properly. Go on, stand there.
- There. You see them, don't you?
- That's me! Only I'm head boy.
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup.
And bloody hell! I'm Quidditch captain
too!
I look good.
Harry, do you think this mirror shows
the future?
How can it? Both my parents are dead.
Back again, Harry?
I see that you, like many before
you...
...have discovered the delights of the
Mirror of Erised.
I trust by now you realize what it
does.
Let me give you a clue.
The happiest man on earth...
...would look in the mirror and see
only himself...
...exactly as he is.
So then, it shows us what we want.
Whatever we want.
Yes. And no.
It shows us nothing more or less...
...than the deepest and most desperate
desires of our hearts.
Now you, Harry, who have never known
your family...
...you see them standing beside you.
But remember this, Harry.
This mirror gives us neither
knowledge...
...or truth.
Men have wasted away in front of it.
Even gone mad.
That is why tomorrow, it will be moved
to a new home.
And I must ask you...
...not to go looking for it again.
It does not do to dwell on dreams...
...and forget to live.
I had you looking in the wrong
section. How could I be so stupid?
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit
of light reading.
This is light?
Of course! Here it is!
Nicholas Flamel is the only known
maker of the Philosopher's Stone.
The what?
Honestly, don't you two read?
"The Philosopher's Stone is a
legendary substance with astonishing
powers.
It'll transform any metal into pure
gold...
...and produces the Elixir of Life
which will make the drinker immortal."
- Immortal?
- It means you'll never die.
I know what it means!
"The only Stone currently in existence
belongs to Mr. Nicholas Flamel...
...the noted alchemist who last year
celebrated his 665th birthday."
That's what Fluffy's guarding.
That's what's under the trap door. The
Philosopher's Stone.
Don't wish to be rude, but I'm in no
state to entertain.
We know about the Philosopher's Stone.
- We think Snape's trying to steal it.
- Are you still on about him?
We know he's after it. We don't know
why.
Snape is one of the teachers
protecting the Stone. He won't steal
it.
What?
You heard. Come on, I'm a bit
preoccupied today.
Wait a minute. "One of the teachers"?
There are other things defending the
Stone, aren't there?
- Spells, enchantments.
- Right.
Waste of bloody time, if you ask me.
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy.
Ain't a soul knows how, except for me
and Dumbledore.
I shouldn't have told you that. I
should not have told you that.
- Hagrid, what exactly is that?
- That? It's....
I know what that is!
But, Hagrid, how did you get one?
I won it. Off a stranger I met down at
the pub.
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it, as
a matter of fact.
Is that...
...a dragon?
That's not just a dragon. That's a
Norwegian Ridgeback.
My brother works with these in
Romania.
Isn't he beautiful? Oh, bless him.
Look, he knows his mummy.
Hello, Norbert.
- Norbert?
- He's gotta have a name, don't he?
Don't you, Norbert?
He'll have to be trained up a bit, of
course.
Who's that?
Malfoy.
Oh, dear.
Hagrid always wanted a dragon. Told me
so the first time I met him.
It's crazy. And worse, Malfoy knows.
- I don't understand. Is that bad?
- It's bad.
Good evening.
Nothing, I repeat, nothing...
...gives a student the right to walk
about at night.
Therefore, as punishment for your
actions,
50 points will be taken.
- 50?!
- Each.
To ensure it doesn't happen again...
...all four of you will receive
detention.
Excuse me, professor, perhaps I heard
you wrong.
I thought you said the four of us.
No, you heard me correctly.
Honorable as your intentions were, you
too were out of bed after hours.
You will join your classmates in
detention.
A pity they let the old punishments
die.
Was a time detention found you hanging
by your thumbs in the dungeons.
God, I miss the screaming.
You'll be serving detention with
Hagrid tonight.
He's got a little job to do inside the
Dark Forest.
A sorry lot, this, Hagrid.
Good God, you're not still on about
that bloody dragon, are you?
Norbert's gone.
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania to
live in a colony.
That's good, isn't it? He's with his
own kind.
What if he don't like Romania?
What if the other dragons are mean to
him? He's only a baby.
For God's sake, pull yourself
together. You're going into the
Forest.
Got to have your wits about you.
The Forest? I thought that was a joke.
We can't go in there.
Students aren't allowed. And there
are...
...werewolves.
There's more than werewolves in those
trees.
You can be sure of that.
Nighty-night.
Right. Let's go.
Hagrid, what is that?
What we're here for. See that?
That's unicorn blood, that is. I found
one dead a few weeks ago.
Now, this one's been hurt bad by
something.
So, it's our job to go and find the
poor beast.
Ron, Hermione, come with me.
And, Harry, you'll go with Malfoy.
Okay. Then I get Fang.
Fine. Just so you know, he's a bloody
coward.
Wait till my father hears about this.
This is servant's stuff.
If I didn't know better, I'd say you
were scared.
I'm not scared, Potter.
Do you hear that?
Come on, Fang.
Scared!
What is it, Fang?
Harry Potter, you must leave. You are
known to many creatures here.
The Forest is not safe at this time.
Especially for you.
What was that thing you saved me from?
A monstrous creature. It is a terrible
crime to slay a unicorn.
Drinking its blood will keep you alive
even if you are an inch from death.
But at a terrible price. For you have
slain something so pure...
...that the moment the blood touches
your lips, you will have a half-life.
A cursed life.
- Who would choose such a life?
- Can you think of no one?
Do you mean to say that that thing
that killed the unicorn...
...that was drinking its blood, that
was Voldemort?
Do you know what is hidden in the
school at this very moment?
The Philosopher's Stone.
Harry!
Hello there, Firenze. See you've met
our young Mr. Potter.
You all right there, Harry?
Harry Potter, this is where I leave
you.
You're safe now. Good luck.
You mean, You-Know-Who is out there
right now in the Forest?
But he's weak. He's living off the
unicorns.
Don't you see? We had it wrong.
Snape doesn't want the Stone for
himself. He wants it for Voldemort.
With the Elixir of Life, Voldemort
will be strong again.
He'll come back.
But if he comes back...
...you don't think he'll try to kill
you, do you?
If he'd had the chance, he might have
tried tonight.
And to think I've been worrying about
my Potions final.
Hang on a minute. We're forgetting one
thing.
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always
feared?
Dumbledore. As long as Dumbledore is
around, Harry, you're safe.
As long as Dumbledore is around, you
can't be touched.
I'd heard Hogwarts'final exams were
frightful, but I found that enjoyable.
Speak for yourself. All right there,
Harry?
- My scar. It keeps burning.
- It's happened before.
- Not like this.
- You should see the nurse.
I think it's a warning. It means
danger's coming.
- Of course!
- What is it?
Isn't it odd that what Hagrid wants
more than anything is a dragon...
...and a stranger just happens to have
one?
How many people wander around with
dragon eggs?
Why didn't I see it before?
Who gave you the egg? What did he look
like?
I never saw his face. He kept his hood
up.
You and this stranger must have
talked.
He wanted to know what sort of
creatures I looked after.
I said, "After Fluffy, a dragon's
gonna be no problem."
- Was he interested in Fluffy?
- Of course he was interested.
How often do you come across a
three-headed dog?
But I told him, "The trick with any
beast is to know how to calm him."
Take Fluffy, for example. Play him
music and he falls straight to sleep.
I shouldn't have told you that.
Where are you going?
We have to see Dumbledore.
Immediately!
I'm afraid he's not here.
He received an urgent owl from the
Ministry of Magic and left.
He's gone? But this is important!
This is about the Philosopher's Stone!
- How do you know--?
- Someone's going to try and steal it.
I don't know how you know, but I
assure you it is well protected.
Now would you go back to your
dormitories? Quietly.
That was no stranger Hagrid met. It
was Snape.
Which means he knows how to get past
Fluffy.
- And with Dumbledore gone--
- Good afternoon.
What would three young Gryffindors...
...be doing inside on a day like this?
- We were just--
- You ought to be careful.
People will think you're...
...up to something.
Now what do we do?
We go down the trap door. Tonight.
Trevor.
Trevor, go! You shouldn't be here!
Neither should you. You're sneaking
out again, aren't you?
- Neville, listen. We were--
- No, I won't let you!
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble
again. I'll fight you.
Neville, I'm really sorry about this.
Petrificus Totalus.
You're a little scary sometimes, you
know that?
Brilliant, but scary.
Let's go.
- Sorry.
- It's for your own good, you know.
- You stood on my foot!
- Sorry.
Alohomora.
Wait a minute. He's...
...snoring.
Snape's already been here. He's put a
spell on the harp.
It's got horrible breath.
- We have to move its paw.
- What?
Come on!
Okay. Push.
I'll go first. Don't follow until I
give you a sign.
If something bad happens, get
yourselves out.
Does it seem a bit quiet to you?
The harp.
It's stopped playing.
Jump!
Lucky this plant thing's here, really.
Stop moving, both of you. This is
Devil's Snare.
You have to relax. If you don't, it
will only kill you faster.
Kill us faster? Oh, now I can relax!
Hermione!
- Now what are we gonna do?
- Just relax!
- Hermione, where are you?
- Do what I say! Trust me.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- He's not relaxing, is he?
- Apparently not.
- We've gotta do something.
- What?
I remember reading something in
Herbology.
Devil's Snare, Devil's Snare. It's
deadly fun...
...but will sulk in the sun! That's
it! It hates sunlight.
Lumus Solem.
- Ron, you okay?
- Yeah.
Lucky we didn't panic.
Lucky Hermione pays attention in
Herbology.
What is that?
I don't know. Sounds like wings.
Curious. I've never seen birds like
these.
They're not birds. They're keys.
And I'll bet one of them fits that
door.
- What's this all about?
- I don't know.
Strange.
Alohomora!
Well, it was worth a try.
What will we do? There must be a
thousand keys.
We want a big, old-fashioned one.
Probably rusty.
I see it! The one with the broken
wing.
What's wrong?
It's too simple.
Go on! If Snape could catch it on that
old broomstick, you can.
You're the youngest Seeker in a
century.
This complicates things a bit.
Catch the key!
Hurry up!
I don't like this. I don't like this
at all.
Where are we? A graveyard.
This is no graveyard.
It's a chessboard.
There's the door.
Now what do we do?
It's obvious, isn't it? We've got to
play our way across the room.
Harry, you take the empty bishop's
square.
Hermione, you'll be the queen-side
castle.
As for me, I'll be a knight.
What happens now?
Well, white moves first.
And then...
...we play.
Ron, you don't suppose this is going
to be like...
...real wizard's chess, do you?
You there, D-5.
Yes, Hermione.
I think this is gonna be exactly like
wizard's chess.
Castle to E-4!
Pawn to C-3!
- Wait a minute.
- You understand right, Harry.
Once I make my move, the queen will
take me.
Then you're free to check the king.
- No. Ron, no!
- What is it?
- He's going to sacrifice himself.
- No, there must be another way!
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting
that Stone or not?
Harry, it's you that has to go on. I
know it.
Not me. Not Hermione. You.
Knight to H-3.
Check.
Ron!
No, don't move! Don't forget, we're
still playing.
Checkmate.
Take care of Ron. Then go to the
owlery.
Send a message to Dumbledore. Ron's
right.
I have to go on.
You'll be okay, Harry. You're a great
wizard. You really are.
Not as good as you.
Me? Books and cleverness. There are
more important things.
Friendship and bravery. And, Harry,
just be careful.
You?
No, it can't be. Snape, he was the--
Yes, he does seem the type, doesn't
he?
Next to him, who would suspect...
...poor, stuttering Professor
Quirrell?
But that day, during the Quidditch
match, Snape tried to kill me.
No, dear boy. I tried to kill you!
If Snape's cloak hadn't caught fire
and broken my eye contact...
...I would have succeeded.
Even with Snape muttering his
counter-curse.
Snape was trying to save me?
I knew you were a danger to me,
especially after Halloween.
- Then you let the troll in!
- Very good, Potter, yes.
Snape, unfortunately, wasn't fooled.
While everyone ran about, he went to
the third floor to head me off.
He, of course, never trusted me again.
He rarely left me alone. But he
doesn't understand.
I'm never alone. Never.
Now, what does this mirror do?
I see what I desire.
I see myself holding the Stone. But
how do I get it?
Use the boy.
Come here, Potter! Now!
Tell me, what do you see?
What is it? What do you see?
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore.
I've won the house cup.
He lies.
Tell the truth! What do you see?
- Let me speak to him.
- Master, you are not strong enough.
I have strength enough for this.
Harry Potter...
...we meet again.
Voldemort.
Yes. You see what I've become?
See what I must do to survive?
Live off another. A mere parasite.
Unicorn blood can sustain me...
...but it cannot give me a body of my
own.
But there is something that can.
Something that, conveniently enough,
lies in your pocket.
Stop him!
Don't be a fool.
Why suffer an horrific death...
...when you can join me and live?
Never!
Bravery. Your parents had it too.
Tell me, Harry...
...would you like to see your mother
and father again?
Together...
...we can bring them back.
All I ask is for something in return.
That's it, Harry.
There is no good and evil.
There is only power...
...and those too weak to seek it.
Together, we'll do extraordinary
things.
Just give me the Stone!
You liar!
Kill him!
- What is this magic?
- Fool, get the Stone!
Good afternoon, Harry.
- Tokens from your admirers?
- Admirers?
What happened in the dungeons between
you and Professor Quirrell is a
secret.
So, naturally, the whole school knows.
I see that your friend Ronald has
saved you the trouble...
...of opening your Chocolate Frogs.
Ron was here? Is he all right? What
about Hermione?
Fine. They're both just fine.
- What happened to the Stone?
- Relax, dear boy.
The Stone has been destroyed.
My friend Nicholas and I have had a
little chat...
...and agreed it was best all around.
But then, Flamel, he'll die, won't he?
He has enough Elixir to set his
affairs in order.
But yes, he will die.
How is it I got the Stone, sir?
One minute I was staring in the mirror
and--
You see, only a person...
...who wanted to find the Stone, find
it...
...but not use it, would be able to
get it.
That is one of my more brilliant
ideas.
And between you and me, that is saying
something.
Does that mean, with the Stone gone,
that Voldemort can never come back?
I'm afraid...
...there are ways in which he can
return.
Harry, do you know why...
...Professor Quirrell couldn't bear to
have you touch him?
It was because of your mother. She
sacrificed herself for you.
And that kind of act leaves a mark.
No, this kind of mark cannot be seen.
- It lives in your very skin.
- What is it?
Love, Harry. Love.
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans.
I was most unfortunate in my youth to
come across a vomit-flavored one.
And since then, I've lost my liking
for them.
But I think I could be safe...
...with a nice toffee.
Alas!
Earwax.
- All right there, Ron?
- All right. You?
All right. Hermione?
Never better.
Another year gone.
And now, as I understand it, the house
cup needs awarding.
And the points stand thus:
In fourth place, Gryffindor with 312
points.
Third place, Hufflepuff with 352
In second place...
...Ravenclaw with 426 points.
And in first place...
...with 472 points, Slytherin house.
Nice one, mate.
Yes, well done, Slytherin. Well done.
However, recent events must be taken
into account.
And I have a few last-minute points to
award.
To Miss Hermione Granger, for the cool
use of intellect...
...while others were in grave peril...
...50 points.
Good job.
Second, to Mr. Ronald Weasley, for the
best-played game of chess...
...that Hogwarts has seen these many
years, 50 points.
And third...
...to Mr. Harry Potter...
...for pure nerve and outstanding
courage...
...I award Gryffindor house 60 points.
We're tied with Slytherin!
Finally, it takes a great deal of
bravery to stand up to your enemies...
...but a great deal more to stand up
to your friends.
I award 10 points...
...to Neville Longbottom.
Assuming that my calculations are
correct...
...I believe that a change of
decoration is in order.
Gryffindor wins the house cup.
Come on, now. Hurry up, you'll be
late.
Train's leaving. Go on. Come on, hurry
up.
- Come on, Harry.
- One minute.
Thought you were leaving without
saying goodbye, did you?
This is for you.
Thanks, Hagrid.
Go on. On with you. On with you now.
Oh, listen, Harry.
If that dolt of a cousin of yours,
Dudley, gives you any grief...
...you could always threaten him...
...with a nice pair of ears to go with
his tail.
But we're not allowed to do magic away
from Hogwarts. You know that.
I do. But your cousin don't, do he?
Feels strange to be going home,
doesn't it?
I'm not going home.
Not really.